Hello everyone, today we invited the best bass instrument designer, Wes Lechmech and Wes Lechmech
to perform a special interview with the Chinese module community
The one on my left is Wes Lechmech, the designer of the bass instrument
and on this side is Wes Lechmech, the developer of the bass instrument
The next interview will be held in English
The translation will be published in the official account
The event is a lot of space for young people and young people to perform
and I think that's very important for building up the community
You mentioned that you were mostly engaged in the module community last weekend
and that's your other time
So not only preparing two days in a row, but also we had a performance in the main event
and also one after party
What are your impressions for the module community?
It feels like I felt really at home because one of the other people who make modules since
have been my friends for a long time
and I met them all here and also met a lot of Chinese people
and it's been very welcoming
Thank you so much
Which part of the module community was considered your favorite part?
I think the performances, especially the short slots where people could try out new things
Another question is there are also many independent developers from China
like Sun Tzu, Wyn Rikiat and also Cody Inspire
and Hong Chi, you know him
So are there any interesting products or ideas you find interesting from them?
Yeah, I think Hong Chi is always inspiring
Very great thinking behind modules
It was great to see there is more, like coding inspired also, very interesting stuff
Thank you
So now we begin with some questions for your coming for Bazel Instrument
So firstly, as a global viewer of the brand, can you describe Bazel Instrument in one or three words?
I think the most important for us is to have fun with the instruments
So I have fun and also we do a lot of compact things
like compact instruments, so maybe these two birds would be...
And I can add inspiring
So it would be fun, compact and inspiring
While that could make those beginners or someone else who have a good global viewer of the Bazel Instrument
So are there any consistent goals or principles when you are designing your own product?
I think these three words really, I think the inspiring factor and like keeping it musical
So we try to not design like every single control from a technical perspective, but from a musical goal
So you have one knob and it doesn't need to be like setting analog capacitors anywhere
It's like most of our designs are digital
And even the analog ones, they have some like macro controls
and there is always some musical intention behind every single control
So we think about pots more like musical controls, not like technical controls
So could you share one of the interesting stories when you develop some of your product?
I need to think about this one
It's interesting, I mean like most recently I was like telling this joke but I don't know if it's true or not
but I was telling somebody as a joke that the Citadel was designed by a YouTube commenter
Yeah, that's not true
That's not true, you designed it before
So if we are going to have some new ideas or new product we want to have, we can comment on your YouTube channel
Yes, we do follow the users and we follow their suggestions
So we are like always happy to develop people's ideas but this actually one most of our ideas
Yeah, it was your idea
So name one, base of product, that's your favorite?
If it was a Euroric module, I think I could not live without the Neotrinity
Neotrinity, yes definitely like a control center and like CV recorder, gas recorder
What about you?
Yeah, for me I really like, even though I wasn't working on it, I really like the dark matter
for like the way how it crunches the sound and you can do like a lot of experimental stuff with it, noisy stuff
So that's my favorite
Dark matter, so we are using Neotrinity, what you usually use, F4 and other advanced tips for using that
So with Neotrinity we were like rethinking like what modulation is and how you would want to do complex modulation from a musical perspective
So there are like three different ways of creating modulation and they all have this gestural control that you can like record the knob for it
for instance and then it keeps repeating itself so that it's sort of like a looper but for modulation
and I think this is like very like direct musical way of expressing yourself and translating the musical idea into the sound
Good, then recently the Caso series like the standalone one are really popular among the YouTube channels and also in China
and also this Saturday we just released like last month, so how did it come up with an idea of doing such a series of product?
Yeah, it started like many years ago when I was designing the first Caso series that was like 10 years ago
that came up with the idea to make like modular send power by batteries like as compact as possible
And also cheap and affordable for everyone because modular is, can be expensive?
Yes, there was like the first Caso series which there were three like modules, synthesizer, draw machine and also like arpeggio note playing machine
So the Caso 2 is like reworked the first Caso series with like more some fidelity and more some possibilities
So that's our like favorite product because it's approachable by even the beginners but also people use it in their like live concerts as well
So even though it's like small but very beverage you can also use it for big shows
Since they are like a platform as I mentioned you can switch firmware using any USB cable
What would be the next firmware for the Caso series?
Can we have a little bit of a spoiler about it?
Yeah, is that here?
So there's a prototype about the new series, the new firmware which is called the Alchemist
So what is the Alchemist? Can we have a little bit of a spoiler about it?
So the Alchemist is a synthesizer firmware so there are five different synthesis modes that are very flexible but also like very musical
And I think they complement each other well and what I like is that you can also modulate between the different modes
And you can control like subtractive synthesis with FM synthesis and it becomes like very natural but it would be quite hard to do it
Otherwise you would need like a lot of modular gear to be able to do these kinds of like sounds and transitions
But like here I think it takes like over a decade of like our experience in modular synths and boils it down into something that is just like instantly fun
But there is like more than a decade of work and experience that went into making that
Alright so there's a lot of questions from like lots of beginners when we want to start with your rack first it's like it's expensive and also it's hard to like build something from scratch
So are there any beginner tips?
I think it's great to start with a semi modular because semi modules typically they have everything you need to start
And if you expand from a semi modular I think that's like a great way to start
It would be easier to like have something pre-built that's to have the ability to patch it to something else
Yeah exactly
So if you have to start your rack from scratch and you can only buy one product as the first one from bass on instrument which would be happy
That one is easy it would be the Citadel wave pad
So this is a review December version of the Citadel
Yes because there is a sound source you can put your own sound so you can already start working with some sound aesthetic that you choose
And it gives you a lot of exploration it has MIDI input it has headphone output so it has everything you need to connect with your other gear
And it's fun and also if you expand with like one two three modules from that it has quite powerful modulation source
So you can kind of can bring the system together from the very start and if you expand from that I think we can guarantee it will be fun
Because it might be quite frustrating when you're starting and if you get a VCO and a filter
Yeah that's just like a mono sound
It takes a while you need quite some modules to start to have fun but like with this one it's fun from the start
It's cheap, it's fun and you can enjoy all those modulation and interesting parts of module
Yeah it combines like a lot of modules together which you would need to get separately
Maybe like if you want to like deep modulations you can get of course the Neutronete and similar products but the Vape bar can get you started definitely
Well the final question is share one of your favorite products or modules that's not in the VCO series
Like from other companies
Yeah from other companies
Yeah my favorite is the Metal Fetishist from BodeSense
I've tried that before
Yeah it's like an experimental drum machine, it's like a small tabletop which looks a little bit like a guitar pedal
And it's like very jammable and I use it in my performances
That's a really fun device, also can be combined with a little castle too
Of course, so what's your favorite?
I think my all time favorite have to be Electron Digitone
The first one
I mean the second one is great but I think the first one is already good enough
That's the one that really helped me musically because it's more limited
And that's been one of the most inspiring pieces of gear I had
Well thank you and that's the end of this short interview
Well that's the end of this short interview
Thank you for watching this video and for your attention to our official account and our channel
We will update more of your Chinese videos in the future
Chinese official videos
Thank you